timesheets.com 2019-05-14

# Legal - Privacy - Timesheets.com

**This Version is Effective June 13, 2018**

## Timesheets.com Values Your Privacy

Timeclockonline.com, Inc. doing business as Timesheets.com ("Timesheets.com" "we" or "us") is committed to protecting your privacy and the privacy of your employees and contractors. Timesheets.com is a United States ("US") based company and subject to US law. Information you or your employer provides to Timesheets.com will be used exclusively for the purpose of providing you the services outlined in the website [Terms of Use](https://www.timesheets.com/terms-of-use/). Timesheets.com has customers, staff, and/or contractors who are located in both the US and in other countries. By accessing or using the Services or otherwise providing information to Timesheets.com, you hereby consent to the processing and transfer of information in and to the US and other countries. Timesheets.com may modify and update this Privacy Policy from time to time. If such modifications and updates are made, Timesheets.com will notify you by revising the date at the top of this policy and in some cases by other notification methods as necessary. You are encouraged to review the Privacy Policy on the website from time to time.

## Information We Collect

Timesheets.com collects only information provided by you and/or any of your employees or other associates you enter on the website system by using the contact form, create an account, or enter data such as when a user punches in or out of work on the website. You may assume that any information you provide, other than credit card information which is not stored by Timesheets.com, is stored by Timesheets.com. Information is collected only for the purpose of running or improving Timesheets.com. Typically, the information collected and stored would include your company name, your time, your IP address, any work related data you enter, and your time and expense related data. Information is also stored pertaining to human resource and payroll related information, such as bill or pay rates and performance documents. It is up to you to decide what information you will enter into Timesheets.com, as most information collected is not required and, therefore, it is entered by you optionally to use various features of our service. Timesheets.com does not sell, rent, trade or otherwise disclose personal information to any organization or entity for any use other than legitimate business uses necessary to provide you Services. Timesheets.com will otherwise comply with all local or US legal requirements pertaining to maintaining privacy of the information provided by you and/or any of your employees or identified associates.

Information typically collected, other than information entered by a worker or manager, during normal use of our service includes such things as the following:

  * Device, log and website interaction information including mouse clicks, pages visited, IP address and timestamp of your visits. Recorded data also includes browser and hardware & software platform information.
  * Information from "cookies" and other typical web tracking technologies.
  * Location information is collected only when using GPS related features.

## How Information is Used

Information regarding you and/or your workers are used by Timesheets.com to provide and improve its Services. Information may also be used to send you technical or informational notices, security alerts, and updates. This information may also be used to monitor usage and analyze trends in connection with providing or improving the Services. Finally, information may be used for ancillary purposes like running contests, direct marketing about updates to the Service which may be of interest to you, or other purposes for which you are notified at the time your information is collected.

## How To Get Your Information

All data entered into Timesheets.com is downloadable in several formats from within your account. In addition, Timesheets.com provides a raw data dump file in zip file format that includes all your data as well. This file is available upon request. Please contact Timesheets.com if you would like a dump of your data in the zip format.

## How To Delete Your Information and be Forgotten

Timesheets.com allows customers to request the removal and deletion of personal data by deleting or de-identifying their data within our system. Customer may request their data be deleted from within their accounts. Timesheets.com may retain certain data while backup files are still necessary to retain, or for longer periods as necessitated by law or other legitimate business reasons including anonymous data analysis for process improvement. Upon expiration of an appropriate retention period, bearing in mind reasonable legal and business requirements, personal information will either be destroyed in a secure manner or made unidentifiable so that it cannot be shown to be related to you. When personal information is collected, used or disclosed, reasonable efforts will be made to ensure that it is accurate, up to date, and complete.

## Information Shared

In the course of running Timesheets.com it is sometimes necessary to share information you have provided. Information which will be shared is as follows or as otherwise described in this policy.

  * With vendors: Vendors such as software and database development consultants or others may need to have access to internal systems to carry out their assignments.
  * With Purchasing Entities: Timesheets.com may be called upon to provide data during negotiations for financing, or for the sales of Timesheets.com or its assets.
  * With Your Consent: Timesheets.com may share information if you direct us to or with your consent.
  * With Law Enforcement: Timesheets.com may share data if compelled or otherwise directed to do so by law enforcement or the courts.
  * To Protect Timesheets.com and its Employees: Data may be shared in the unusual event it is required to protect Timesheets.com's employees, their safety, or their property.

Anonymous data may be shared so that it could not reasonably be used to identify people or organizations.

In certain situations, we may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

## Your Privacy Controls

### Your Timesheets.com Account

You may edit or delete your account information at any time by logging into your account. Please note that certain information may be retained for legitimate business purposes or as may be otherwise required by law.

### Cookies

In order to use Timesheets.com you must accept cookies. Cookies are necessary tracking information that our Service needs to use in order to work normally. Most browsers are set to receive cookies automatically by default.

### Location Information

Timesheets.com only tracks location information for specific users that you specify you would like us track. Otherwise, Timesheets,.com does not collect GPS information.

### Account Notification

You may opt out of receiving business related account notifications from Timesheets.com by logging into your account and changing your preferences.

### Promotional Information

You may opt out of receiving promotional communications from Timesheets.com by following the instructions in those messages, usually by clicking the 'unsubscribe' link at the bottom of such messages. If you opt out, we may still send you non-promotional communications, such as those necessary for you to administer your account.

## Your California Privacy Rights

Timesheets.com uses a third party for email marketing. To opt out of having information about you shared with third parties such as email marketers for direct marketing purposes, please contact us.

## Privacy Shield - for EU Customers

Timesheets.com complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries transferred to the United States pursuant to Privacy Shield. Timesheets.com has certified that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles with respect to such data. If there is any conflict between the policies in this privacy policy and data subject rights under the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification page, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>

U.S. Federal Trade Commission enforcement: Timesheets.com's commitments under the Privacy Shield are subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the United States Federal Trade Commission.

 **Access and Choice:** Pursuant to the Privacy Shield Frameworks, EU individuals have the right to obtain our confirmation of whether we maintain personal information relating to you in the United States. Upon request, we will provide you with access to the personal information that we hold about you. You may also may correct, amend, or delete the personal information we hold about you. An individual who seeks access, or who seeks to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data transferred to the United States under Privacy Shield, should direct their query to our contact form, or by using the contact information listed below. If requested to remove data, we will respond within a reasonable timeframe.

We will provide an individual opt-out or opt-in choice before we share your data with third parties other than our agents, or before we use it for a purpose other than which it was originally collected or subsequently authorized. To request to limit the use and disclosure of your personal information, please submit a written request to our contact form, or by using the contact information listed below.

 **Third parties who may receive personal data:** Timesheets.com uses a limited number of third-party service providers to assist it in providing services to customers. These third party providers offer technical assistance to Timesheets.com, perform database monitoring and other technical operations, assist with the transmission of data, and provide storage services. These third parties may access, process, or store personal data in the course of providing their services. Timesheets.com maintains contracts with these third parties restricting their access, use and disclosure of personal data in compliance with its Privacy Shield obligations set forth in this policy.

Timesheets.com's accountability for personal data that it receives in the United States under the Privacy Shield and subsequently transfers to a third party is described in the Privacy Shield Principles. In particular, Timesheets.com remains responsible and liable under the Privacy Shield Principles if third-party agents that it engages to process the personal data on its behalf do so in a manner inconsistent with the Principles, unless Timesheets.com proves that it is not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage.

 **Inquiries and complaints:** If you believe Timesheets.com maintains your personal data in one of the services within the scope of our Privacy Shield certification, you may direct any inquiries or complaints concerning our Privacy Shield compliance to us.

In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, Timesheets.com commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information transferred to the United States pursuant to Privacy Shield. European Union individuals with Privacy Shield inquiries or complaints should first contact us via our contact form, or by using the contact information listed below. Timesheets.com will respond within 45 days.

If Timesheets.com fails to respond within that time, or if its response does not address your concern, Timesheets.com has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the Privacy Shield Principles to an independent dispute resolution mechanism, the BBB EU PRIVACY SHIELD, operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed, please visit [www.bbb.org/EU-privacy-shield/for-eu-consumers](https://www.bbb.org/EU-privacy-shield/for-eu-consumers) for more information and to file a complaint. This service is provided free of charge to you.

If your Privacy Shield complaint cannot be resolved through the above channels, under certain conditions, you may invoke binding arbitration for some residual claims not resolved by other redress mechanisms. See Privacy Shield Annex 1 at <https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=ANNEX-I-introduction>. Timesheets.com commits to cooperate with EU data protection authorities (DPAs) and comply with the advice given by such authorities with regard to human resources data transferred from the EU in the context of the employment relationship.

## Publicity

By using the Timesheets.com service, you grant Timesheets.com the right to list your "company" or "entity" name on its customer list, which may appear in its marketing materials. Individuals will not be listed, nor will Timesheets.com list any specific information about your account. You may request to be removed from this list at any time. In addition, permission may be requested to list your name and a statement about Timesheets.com among Timesheets.com's customer testimonials. If you grant this permission, your name and comment will appear among other customer testimonials.

## Contact Us

Questions, comments or complaints regarding this policy and related matters may be sent electronically to us by [clicking here](https://secure.timesheets.com/default.cfm?page=Contact) or by mailing us at the following address.

Timesheets.com   
Attn: Privacy   
155 San Pedro Circle  
San Jose, CA 95110
